Hold your noise!
Hold your noise, you little devil,
or I'll cut your throat!
- Tell us your, name! Quick!
- Pip!
- Once more! Give it mouth!
- Shh!
- Pip, sir! No, sir, please.
Got wittles on you, boy?
You got wittles on you?
No, sir!
Come here.
What fat cheeks you got.
Darn me if I couldn't eat 'em.
Where's your mother?
There, sir!
Also Georgiana, sir.
My mother and brothers too.
Orphan, eh?
Who d'you live with?
Supposin' I let you live.
My sister, sir, Mrs Joe Gargery,
wife of Joe Gargery, the blacksmith.
Blacksmith, eh?
You know what a file is?
- You know what wittles is?
- Yes, sir, food, sir.
I ain't alone, as you may think I am.
There's a young man hid with me in
comparison with which I am an angel,
and he has a secret way of getting at a boy,
and at his heart, and at his liver,
so that they may be roasted and ate.
It is in vain for a boy to hide
from that young man.
Now, you bring me tomorrow morning early,
in this graveyard,
that file and them wittles,
never daring to say a word,
and I will do what I can to keep
that young man out of your insides.
Understand?
- Speak it out!
- Yes, sir!
Now get you home.
There you are, Pip!
Ah, Your sister's been out
a dozen times looking for you.
Now, listen, she's on the rampage
and she's got Tickler with her.
Now, I'll do what I can but you best
get in there behind the door.
- Now... You ready?
- Where have you been?
Wearing me out with fret and worry!
I said, "Where have you been?"
- The churchyard.
- The churchyard!
If it weren't for me you would've been
to the churchyard years ago, and stayed there!
- Who brought you up by hand?
- You did!
Why did I, I should like to know!
Fetch the tar water!
There's no need for tar water, my love.
It's Christmas.
Fetch it!
Bad enough having to be a blacksmith's
wife, without having to mother you, too.
- You're driving me to the churchyard.
- You all right?
You'd like that, both of you, I suppose.
Tar water. You be careful.
Table! Now!
There's another convict escaped from the Hulks.
What might he have done, the convict?
Murder most likely.
That's why they put them in the Hulks,
because they murder.
- Murder?
- Murder and robbing.
That's too many questions!
Where's that bread gone?
I ate it.
You did, did you?
Sir. Sir...
Did you bring it, boy?
Yes, sir. Here.
What's in the bottle?
- Brandy.
- Here. Here.
- You brought no-one with you?
- No, sir!
- And you asked no-one to follow?
- I wouldn't do that, sir.
I'm glad you enjoy the pie.
Oh, thankee, my boy, I do. I do.
- There'll be none left for him!
-"Him"?
- Who's "him"?
- The young man you spoke of.
Who wants to eat my liver.
Oh, him.
He won't want no pie.
He looked as if he did.
Looked? What d'you mean, looked?
I saw him.
- When?
- Just now.
- Where?
- Down by the river.
What with...
Dressed like me with a bruised face?
- Here? Badly bruised?
- Yes, sir.
Give me the file, boy!
Hunt him down like a dog I will.
- Goodbye, then, sir.
- Let him go free?
Merry Christmas, sir.
- Let him make a fool of me again?
- Goodbye.
That villain. I'll take him
to the bottom of the river...
♪ I On Christmas day, ♪
♪ on Christmas day ♪
♪ I And ail the souls on ♪
♪ earth shalt sing ♪
♪ On Christmas day in the morning ♪
♪ Then let us all rejoice and sing ♪
♪ On Christmas day, ♪
♪ on Christmas day ♪
Beautiful.
A beautiful piece of meat, that is.
For the great feast we are about to receive,
- Thanks to you, ma'am...
- Hear, hear.
May the good Lord make us truly thankful.
- Amen.
Did you hear that? Be grateful!
Especially, my boy, as to those
what brought you up by hand.
Why is it that the young are never grateful?
- Naturally wicious!
- Wicious little ferret.
What?
They're not lovely. They're wicious.
More gravy, Mr Wopsle?
Mmm-hmm.
Mmm.
Oh, I nearly forgot!
Ladies and gentlemen, please do leave
a little room for the savoury pork pie
so kindly provided for by dear Mr Pumblechook.
No more than you deserve, ma'am.
I'll get it now.
Shall I get it now?
I often say a slice of savoury pork pie
will sit on top of anything
you care to mention...
Are you all right?
...and do no harm.
Especially with a little brandy.
Wise words, as always.
It's in here somewhere.
At least it was here. It's gone!
There's tar water in the brandy!
Pip!
Where do you think you're going, boy?
Oh, that is hot, yeah.
Well done, blacksmith. Well done.
Nasty vicious characters, both of them.
Not the kind you'd want to
stumble upon alone, eh?
Anybody here seen anything of such a gang?
- Nothing, Sergeant.
- Thank you, ma'am.
Your health, sir.
- Thank you, sir.
- A fine job.
We found them filed clean through.
But no matter. We'll have
'em back on him in no time.
Course, if any of you gentlemen
fancy some sport...
- Oh, yes.
- Willingly.
Right, outside. Fall in.
Jump to it.
Come on, let's be having you.
Out you come, Pip.
I hope we don't find 'em, Joe.
I hope so too, old chap.
I hope so too.
Over here, Sergeant!
Come here!
You, man, break it off.
Break it off.
Get them. Go.
Get out there, you cowardly bastard.
Move. Move.
I've got him!
Break it off! Break it off!
What are you waiting for? Get out there!
Go on, get in!
Let me at him!
He tried to murder me!
- I took him!
- Get those leg irons over here.
He tried to murder me!
Let him go free?
Let him profit from me again and again?
Let's put him down.
- He tried to murder me!
- Quiet, you!
I should have been a dead man,
if you hadn't got here.
I wish to say something.
- A confession if you like.
- Wait.
Go on.
A man can't starve.
I took, stole, some wittles up at the village.
And a file too.
And I'll tell you from where.
The blacksmith's.
Brandy and a pie.
Have you missed such an article as a pie,
blacksmith?
- My wife did.
- So you're the blacksmith, are you?
Then I'm sorry to say I've eat your pie.
God knows you're welcome to it.
We don't know what you've done,
but we wouldn't wish you to starve
to death for it, would us, Pip?
No.
Pip?
Move on!
Swing your legs in there.
I say, Pip, old chap!
What a scholar you are!
I should like to be, some day.
Here, read it, Joe.
Read it.
My dear Joe,
I hope you are quite well.
I shall soon be able to teach you Joe.
- And what larks!
- Larks.
It's a J.
An O.
That's the best O I ever saw.
It's astonishing!
How interesting this reading is!
Perhaps I could teach you one day, Joe.
Perhaps.
Be it so, be it so.
But I fear I am most awful...
Awful... Dull.
Not like you, young scholar!
Ever the best of friends.
Thanks, Pip.
Ever the best of friends, Joe.
And when you're apprenticed to me, what larks.
Gargery!
She must be, what, two mile off?
Best be getting back, old chap.
You're not too quick for me yet.
Now, if this boy ain't grateful,
he never will be.
I only hope he won't be pampered.
She ain't in that line, Mum, have no fear.
- "She"?
- Well, Miss Havisham ain't a he, is she?
Even you ain't as dull as that!
Well put, ma'am. Good indeed.
- Mr Pumblechook...
- Her tenant, don't you see?
...goes to pay his rent
and Miss Havisham says,
does he know a boy who might go
and play there for her pleasure?
And Mr Pumblechook always being
considerate and thoughtful of us...
No more than you deserve, ma'am.
...mentions this boy prancing here.
To go straightaway!
For all we know our fortune might be made
and all he has to do is play!
I don't want to.
You listen to me, ungrateful wretch.
Want to mix with people of quality and breeding
or stay here and rot
with this great lumpen noodle?
- Stay here.
- What?
What?
Breathe in. Breathe.
Six sixes.
36.
- Minus 35.
- One.
Plus 119.
119...
Um, 120.
Divided by 84.
Your answer, please, boy.
Your answer.
So start again.
12 times 39.
Four times 17.
Too slow. 68.
Nine times 13.
117.
Now, boy, remember your station
and let your conduct be a credit as to
those which brought you up by hand.
Ow!
- Look, the clock's stopped.
- Never mind the clock...
- What name?
- Pumblechook.
Quite right.
Do you wish to see Miss Havisham?
- Well, if Miss Havisham wishes to see me!
- She don't.
Come along, boy.
Boy!
Are you frightened?
I don't know.
Go in, then.
After you, miss.
Who is it?
Pip, ma'am.
Pip?
Pumblechook's boy, come to, uh, play.
Oh.
Ah, yes.
Um...
Come nearer.
Let me look at you.
Look at me!
You're not afraid of a woman who's
never seen the sun since you were born?
No, ma'am.
Then come closer.
Hmm.
Now, I sometimes have sick fancies.
And, um, I have a sick fancy
that I want to see some play.
Um, so play.
Go on, play.
Play.
- Are you sullen and obstinate?
- No, ma'am!
I am very sorry for you
and sorry that I can't play.
But if you complain of me
I will get into trouble with my sister,
so I would play if I could,
but it's just so new here.
Call Estella! Estella!
Estella!
Mmm.
Your own one day, my dear,
and you will use it well.
Now. Let me see you
play cards with him.
But he's a common labouring boy.
You can break his heart.
What do you play, boy?
Nothing but, "Beggar My Neighbour", miss.
So...
Beggar him.
- The jack of diamonds.
- "Jack"!
He calls the knaves "jack", this boy.
And what coarse hands he has,
and what thick boots.
He's nothing but a stupid, clumsy labouring boy.
What do you think of her?
You say nothing of her.
I don't like to say.
Whisper in my ear.
Hm.
What do you think?
I think she is very proud.
Anything else?
I think...
I think she is very pretty.
Anything else?
I think she is very insulting.
I think I should like to go home.
What?
And never see her again?
I think I'd like to see her again.
Then you shall.
But when, when shall I have you here again?
Today is Wednesday.
No Wednesdays, Thursdays, Fridays here,
no days of the week, no weeks of the year.
No... Come again after 6 nights.
Estella, take him down.
Feed him.
"And the Lord said unto... Unto...
"...unto Aaron,
"Thou and thy sons
and thy father's house..."
Good gracious, what is going on?
Enough! Enough, I say!
Back to your form, Pip.
Now, let us read together.
Quietly.
"And the Lord said
"unto Aaron...
"...Thou and thy sons..."
I wonder if you might teach me.
Teach you what, Pip?
Everything-
I want to know everything.
Everything?
Goodness, well, that might take a little time.
Pip, whatever for?
Do you know the name of the house, boy?
It is Satis House.
Is that Greek or Latin?
Greek or Latin or Hebrew or all three,
for "enough".
Enough House. That's a curious name.
Don't loiter!
It meant, when it was given,
that whoever had this house
would want for nothing else.
They must have been easily satisfied.
Is this him? Is this the boy?
- None of your business.
- Well! Of all the...
Will she see us today?
We have been waiting!
- Waiting all morning!
- We only wish to help.
Miss Havishams poor relations.
She calls them her vultures.
- The little bitch.
- Ignore them.
- So are they your relations too?
- Certainly not.
I have no relations.
- Then Miss Havisham is not your...
- Well?
- Well, miss?
- Am I pretty?
Yes. You are very pretty.
Am I insulting?
No.
Well, not so much as last time.
Why don't you cry?
Because I don't want to.
Whom have we here?
Ah. So you're the boy, are you?
Well, I have a pretty large experience of
boys, and you're a bad set of fellows.
Behave yourself.
You're to wait here in the ballroom.
What do you think it is?
A cake.
A bride's cake.
Mine!
Take my hand, walk with me.
Today is my birthday.
- Many happy ret...
- I will not have it spoken of!
No. On this day of the year,
long before you were born,
this heap of decay was brought here...
We've worn away together.
Mice have gnawed at it.
And sharper teeth than mice have gnawed at me.
When the ruin is complete,
when they lay me dead in my bride's dress,
on the bride's table,
the curse will be finished on him.
On who, Miss Havisham?
Miss Havisham. How well you look!
- Happy birthday.
- Indeed.
Ah, the vultures.
Estella, feed the boy.
Who are you?
Who let you in?
Who gave you leave to prowl about?
Estella.
Estella?
That witch!
- Take that back!
- I will not!
- You will take that back.
- Fight me, then.
Regular rules.
Come to the ground!
Fight me, fight me.
That means you won.
Honour is satisfied. Much obliged.
Good afternoon!
You are to return the day after tomorrow
at noon, alternate days after that.
Expect no reward.
You may kiss me.
If you like.
Now, then,
the Kings of England.
- Henry III, Richard...
- Edward I.
- II and III.
- Richard.
- Richard the...
- Richard II.
- Henry the...
How do you manage it, Biddy?
- Manage what?
- To know so much.
I suppose I catch it.
Like a cough.
Mnmum
♪ Old Clem, beat it out, ♪
♪ beat it out ♪
♪ Old Clem, ♪
♪ with a clink for the stout ♪
♪ Old Clem, with a... ♪
Something wrong, old chap?
I wish you hadn't taught me
to call knaves jacks.
What's that, Pip?
I wish my boots weren't so thick and my
hands so coarse. I wish I wasn't common!
- May I ref! you a secret?
- I suppose you may.
I don't...
I don't want to be a blacksmith.
I want to be a gentleman.
Oh, I wouldn't if I was you.
Aren't you fond of the forge?
- And Joe?
- Yes.
Then don't you think
you'd be happier as you are?
I have particular reasons.
To do with a certain young lady, I suppose.
Your princess.
One, two, three, four.
One, two, three...
Estella.
What are you doing?
Teaching Pip to dance.
Like a gentleman.
Bring the blacksmith to see me.
Joe.
Oh.
So you are the husband of the sister of the boy?
Being that I have been married to your sister...
Just say yes, Joe.
- By which I mean to say...
- Joe.
Yes, Miss Havisham.
And you have reared the boy with the
intention of making him your apprentice?
You know, Pip, as you and I
ever were the best of friends,
and it were look fofiard to betwixt us
as being calculated to lead to larks.
The boy has made no objection to the trade?
Larks being the great wish of his heart.
Oh, enough! Estella.
Um, bring me that purse.
Yes, um...
Pip has earnt a premium here.
Here are 5 and 20 guineas.
Give it to your new master, Pip.
Now...
You are now a blacksmith.
Goodbye.
You are not ashamed
of being a blacksmith, are you?
No.
Then you are a blacksmith.
Goodbye.
But...
Am I to come again?
No.
Goodbye, Pip.
You have been a good boy.
Goodbye. Goodbye.
Come on. Let's go.
Perhaps we shall meet again.
One day.
It seems unlikely.
Pip. Pip.
Come on, boy.
Pip.
Joe, may I?
Biddy, I wish...
Go on.
Pip?
Biddy, I wish I could fall in love with you.
Oh.
- Can I say this to you?
- Don't mind me.
I wish I could love you and my work
and that I could settle down with Joe
at the forge,
and that we could be sitting here together,
two completely different people.
I do wish I could be content, but...
You cannot.
Might you be content with me?
I might.
But then I'm easily pleased.
Do you think of her very often?
Pip. Pip!
Gentleman to see you.
You are Philip Pirrip,
more commonly known as Pip,
am I right?
- Yes, sir.
- And this is your brother-in-law...
- Joseph, or "Joe" Gargery?
- I am that man.
- And your wife, Mr Gargery?
- Dead, sir.
Bad heart.
Passed away 5 years since,
while on the rampage. I miss her.
- I miss her.
- Condolences, yes.
My name is Daggers.
I'm a lawyer in London.
I'm pretty well known.
And I have some unusual business
to transact with you.
Joseph Gargery, I am the bearer of an offer...
To relieve you of this young fellow,
your apprentice.
I am here to inform you
that he has great expectations.
He has come into a handsome fortune,
and it is the desire of the present
possessor of the fortune
that he be removed
from his present circumstances
and brought up as
a gentleman in London.
Do you have any objections?
- I don't think so.
- There are conditions, of course.
The first being that you always
retain the name Pip.
You've no objections to that, I dare say.
I have no objection.
And the second stipulation,
is that the name of the liberal benefactor
remain a profound secret.
You are positively prohibited
from making any enquiries into this question.
Do you understand?
I understand.
- Mr Gargery?
- Hm?
Mr Gargery, this is for you.
20 guineas.
As compensation for the loss of his services.
Very generous, I think you'd agree.
If you think money can make compensation
for the loss of the little orphan
what come to the forge and was...
- it's time for us, Joe.
- Yes, yes, yes, very noble sentiment.
Very touching, I'm sure.
Do you want the money or no?
- If you're a man, come on!
- Joe.
Bear-baiting and badgering me
in my own home.
- Come on, I say!
- Joe!
- Joe! Enough! Enough!
Joe!
Well, Mr Pip, the sooner
you leave here, the better.
Shall we say one week?
And what will I do in London?
Do?
What will be my trade?
My profession?
A gentleman.
You will be a gentleman.
You will please consider me your guardian now.
Good evening.
Thing is, I always say,
you need your inexpressibles
in something fine, clingy!
A nice lute string, ladies.
No point your inexpressibles
being in nankeen, now, is there?
No point at all.
Nothing clings.
Nothing is expressed.
Mr Pumblechook.
Oh, 7 times 16, your answer, please.
- Mr Pumblechook.
- Too slow, too slow.
- Mr Pumblechook, I have some news.
- Oh?
I've...
Well, I've come into some property.
Oh.
This is a very sweet article
for light summer wear.
- May I?
- You may.
Ah... Feel the knap?
D'you feel that?
Yah.
See how it catches the light?
Extra super fine and quite in vogue
amongst the London gentry. Number 5...
This is you as well.
This is very you.
That will be evening and that will be daytime.
So, best to get them both.
What about some gentleman's boots?
We don't do boots.
Astonishing.
Oi!
For luck!
- Bye, boy.
- Bye, Pip.
So we thought you might like a little erm...
A little something to tempt your appetite.
A cup of tea?
You might enjoy the chocolate...
Pip.
Come closer, come closer.
Come join us.
How handsome you look in your finery.
You remember my cousin Sarah Pocket.
She works for me now.
I employ her.
Miss Havisham, I...
I came to take my leave of you.
- You see, I've...
- Yes, yes.
I've seen Mr Jaggers.
I know all about it.
You are adopted by a mysterious benefactor?
Yes, Miss Havisham.
Isn't that wonderful news, everyone?
- Yes, quite...
- Wonderful.
- Go now. Everyone, go.
All of you, go.
Hmph.
I was, uh, hoping that...
She's abroad, Pip.
Educating for a lady.
Far out of reach.
Prettier than ever.
Admired by all who see her.
Do you feel you have lost her, Pip?
Be patient.
I'm sure your paths will cross.
- I hope so.
- Mm.
Miss Havisham, I wished to say how grateful...
Uh-uh-uh-uh-uh.
Hush now, Pip.
You will always keep the name of Pip, you know.
Go.
Goodbye, Pip.
Hey! Hey!
Here, sir, you want some offal?
Get off!
Excuse me, sir.
Meat!
Lovely meat!
Mr Pip?
Mr Jaggers will be with you shortly, Mr Pip.
He's at the Bailey, getting evidence together.
Whose likenesses are they?
Likenesses?
Why, this is their true selves!
Casts made in Newgate,
fresh from the gallows.
Murderer, and a forger of wills.
Very crafty in particular, this one.
But the evidence was too strong.
Not so crafty now, are you, my friend?
This was his as well. Made a gift
of it to me, just before the end.
They're not worth much, but they're portable,
and they're property.
That's my guiding star, Mr Pip.
- Get hold of portable properly.
- I have no more to say to you.
That's Mr Jaggers now.
I wish to know no more than I know.
Good day, Mr Pip.
- Any more news, Mr Jaggers?
- Get your hands off me!
- Have you paid MrWemmick?
- Yes.
Now let go of my coat.
I trust your journey was satisfactory.
Mr daggers, have you had any
feelings about my claim?
Feelings? Feelings?
We'll have no "feelings" here.
Come on in, Mr Pip.
Move back!
You've met Mr Wemmick.
Sorry, sir.
He keeps the money, so doubtless
you will be seeing a lot of him.
Dear Lord, is that your new suit?
Here.
Tailor, hatter, bootmaker, hosier.
Your credit will be good with all of them.
I've taken the liberty of enrolling you
in a gentlemen's club.
The Finches of the Grove.
Just the thing for gentlemen of distinction.
Your allowance, Mr Pip.
I trust you will find it generous.
Your temporary lodgings
will be at Barnard's Inn.
Quite near here, so I might keep an eye on you.
There you are, sir.
And pull you up when I find you going wrong.
And, you will go wrong, Mr Pip,
not through any fault of mine.
- Mr Pip?
- Mr Pocket?
I am extremely sorry, but I thought that,
coming from the country,
you might like a little fruit.
- Strawberries!
- Oh.
Oh. Strawberry jam!
Mm. Have you seen your lodgings?
- No.
- They're by no means splendid,
but I'm sure that we shan't come to blows.
Put them up.
Come on.
Stand your ground.
Regular rules apply.
I beg your pardon?
The prowling boy.
The pale young gentleman.
I was there with my Aunt Sarah on a trial visit.
Miss Havisham fancied
that she wanted to see me play.
Clearly she didn't take much of a fancy to me.
Poor taste on her part.
But just as well.
Otherwise, I might have been
what-you-called it to Estella.
Affianced. Betrothed.
Engaged.
But, it was not to be.
I'm very sorry.
Sorry?
The girl's a Tartar.
Hard and haughty and...
Thank you.
...Capricious to the last degree.
Brought up by Miss Havisham
to wreak revenge on all the male sex.
Why should she wreak revenge?
Lord, Mr Pip. Don't you know?
Miss Havisham was very rich and very proud,
a spoilt child.
Her mother died when she was young
and her father married again.
His cook would you believe?
And they had a son, Arthur.
Who was... How might I put this?
...Not entirely legitimate.
At this point, I might break off and mention
that in London it's not the custom
to put the knife in the mouth,
- for fear of accidents.
- Sorry.
And also the fork is not generally used
underhand but over.
- Of course. Of course.
- Do you mind?
No, not at all. I'm grateful.
Er... T's, Mr Pip.
You are grateful.
Grateful. Sorry.
Now, um...
Miss Havisham met a certain man
and she loved this man, devotedly, passionately.
Idolised him.
And soon they were engaged.
He persuaded her to buy
her half-brother's share of the brewery
at an immense price,
so that when he was her husband,
he could hold and manage it all.
Well...
The happy day arrived.
The wedding dresses were bought,
the wedding tour planned out.
The wedding guests were invited,
my parents among them.
The feast was laid out.
A great bride cake made.
And the groom wrote her a letter.
And she received the letter
from her brother, Arthur...
- As she was dressing for marriage?
- At 20...
20 minutes to 9.
Of course.
Ah those stopped clocks.
It was a conspiracy between
the groom and her brother,
to defraud Miss Havisham
and break her heart.
No!
And, in that they most surely succeeded.
So, Herbert, what's your line of business?
Well, trade.
That's where the money is.
In the future, I shall trade to Egypt
for silks and spices.
Ceylon for elephant tusks.
But for now?
But for now, I am a clerk in a counting house,
with a sweetheart whom I can't afford to marry.
- Is there profit in being a clerk?
- No.
None whatsoever.
Not a penny.
You know, I don't much care for the name Mr Pip.
I'll tell you what I should like.
Seeing as we are so harmonious
and you have been a blacksmith,
would you mind Handel for a familiar name?
The Harmonious Blacksmith.
It's by Handel.
- Do you mind?
- I would like it very much.
Good!
As Bullfinch of this Grove,
and in the name
of the most honoured Chaffinch...
- Fringillae!
- ...Goldfinch...
Carduelis!
...and Hawfinch.
Coccothraustes!
May the present promotion of good feeling
ever reign predominant
among the noble Finches of the Grove.
Gentlemen...
Huzzah! Huzzah!
For the Finches of the Grove!
I am assured that they are
the most fashionable people.
Believe me. Oh.
You there! New boy. Yes, you there.
Partridge.
Throw me a partridge.
Come on, come on.
Oh, dear. I don't think
he shall do well here.
Pip, isn't it?
- Er, Pip?
- Pirrip.
Pirrip?
Pip Pirrip?
Oh. How remarkable.
And where are your people from?
- My people?
- From Kent.
They're the Kentish Pirrips.
You sound like some sort of apple.
Huzzah!
Noble finches of this grove!
This will just take a moment, my dear.
- He seems very keen.
- I'm sure.
Handel, this is my beloved fiancee, Clara.
- Aren't I the lucky one?
- Herbert, please.
So pleased to meet you. Shall we?
This is far too expensive for you, Herbert.
What are we doing here?
There you are, sir.
Well? What do you think?
It would be at my expense, of course.
You're a clerk, Herbert Pocket.
Well?
Well...
Hurry!
I'd like to meet these extravagant
Finches of yours.
Tomorrow evening.
No ceremony. No dinner dress.
6 o'clock, say?
Give him the money, Wemmick.
Very well, sir.
What shall I make of him, Mr Wemmick?
He's a deep one. Deep.
As Australia.
Don't take it personal, Mr Pip.
It's professional.
Only professional.
I say, if tonight you have nothing better to do,
why don't you come home to Walworth with me?
I don't have much to show you
but there's a garden
and one or two curiosities.
- What?
- Watch this.
I know what you're thinking.
It's like living in the country.
All my own doing.
Please, now...
Let me introduce you to the aged parent.
- Well, Aged P, how are you?
- All right, John, my boy. All right.
This is Mr Pip, Aged P.
Not that he can hear a word I'm saying.
Just nod away at him,
if you don't mind. Nod and wink.
- Now, John...
- Nod.
- Now...
- And wink. Keep nodding. One more.
Nearly time, Aged P. You keep
nodding, I'll heat the poker.
Down the stairs, that's right.
Now, John. Now.
Mr Pip. Mr Pip, if you'd care
to do the honours.
Ooh!
I heard it! I heard it!
- Does Mr Jaggers admire it?
- Never seen it. Never heard of it.
Never seen the Aged.
Never heard of him.
When I come into The Castle,
I leave Mr Jaggers behind.
And if it's not in any way disagreeable to you,
you'll oblige me by doing the same.
Of course. I understand.
I will give you one piece of advice, though.
When you dine with Mr Jaggers tomorrow,
you take a look at his housekeeper, Molly.
His housekeeper? Why?
Just take a look at his
housekeeper and see,
a wild beast tamed.
Now, gentlemen! Gentlemen!
Our generous host, Mr Bentley Drummle.
Oh...
May the present promotion of good feeling
ever reign predominant over the
Noble Finches of the Grove.
See, Bentley, Hold you, you could do it.
Tell me, Pip. Who is the Spider?
That blotchy, sprawly, sulky fellow?
That's Bentley Drummle.
The richest young man in England.
- Is it now?
- He owns most of Derbyshire, apparently.
Bentley Drummle, you say?
Most promising.
Molly.
Make sure that fellow does not have
an empty glass all evening.
Come on!
My money's on Bentley!
I raise you five!
Oh!
A fluke. Pure chance.
Come, come, Bentley, concede defeat.
Pip beat you fair and square.
I was under the impression that
the Finches was a club for gentlemen.
I can't be expected to compete
against country boys.
What do you mean, Mr Drummle?
No slight, I assure you.
In fact, I salute you, Kentish Pirrip!
You have the arms of a blacksmith!
Molly, more wine here.
You talk of strength.
I'll show you strength.
Show them your wrists, Molly.
Come on.
- Master, don't!
- Show them both.
Show them. Show them.
What is that?
Mm.
There's power.
Very few men have the power this woman has.
Gentlemen, I propose a toast.
I drink to you, Mr Drummle.
To your good health, Bentley!
I apologise if anything disagreeable...
Oh, no, no. That's all right.
- I do like that Spider fellow, though.
- Do you? I don't.
No. No, you're right, of course.
Stay as clear of him as you can.
He does have great promise, though.
Indeed, if I were a fortune teller.
But I'm not a fortune teller.
You know what I am, don't you?
Go to bed, Pip.
Good night.
Sir.
Come on! Come on, sir!
Get up!
Someone to see you, sir.
Pepper, I've told you
I'm not to be woken unless the...
How are you, Pip?
I brought you a toasting fork as a present,
you know, for crumpets and the like.
But I see you have no need.
That's... It's perfect,
Joe. Thank you.
- Tea or coffee, sir?
- Oh! Tea, sir, please, if you don't mind.
I find the coffee a little powerful.
- Us two now being alone, sir...
- Sir?
Joe, how can you call me sir?
Us two being now alone, Pip,
I might tell you the reason for me being
in the abode of a gentleman,
which is that I've had a communication
with a certain Miss A.
Miss A? Joe?
Miss 'Avisham. She wishes to see you
on a matter of great import.
Joe, this is my good friend Herbert Pocket.
- Mr Gargery, I've heard a great deal about you.
- Nice to meet you.
Oh? What is there to say?
A very great deal.
Now, suppose we have a celebration?
It takes some getting used to, eh, Joe?
Now, this place may look a little rough
but don't be deceived.
In my opinion, this is the finest
place in London.
Oh, and the pressed duck is superb.
Let him take it, Joe.
Joe.
How do you find London, Mr Gargery?
London! What a place!
What a place!
Course, I wouldn't keep a pig in it myself.
Biddy sends her regards.
She's a teacher now, a good one.
She taught me.
Fork. F-O-R-K.
Knife. N-I-F-E.
I know it's not!
- More wine, Mr Gargery?
- Yes, please.
Joe, please.
There's really no need to be so
conscientious in emptying your glass.
The rim should never touch your nose, Joe.
Gentlemen, if you'll excuse me.
Well, business concluded,
I'll be off.
- You're going now?
- Yes, I am.
- Please, put your money away, Joe.
- No. No, I insist.
- You will not stay the night?
- No, I won't.
Sir! Sir!
For God's sake, Joe, put your money away!
Joe!
- At least, let me walk you to the coach.
- I'll find my way.
But we have barely spoken, Joe.
I wished to show you some sights.
You and me are not two figures
to be together in London.
I'm wrong outside the forge,
and the kitchen and the marshes.
You come sometime and you put your
head in at the window at the forge
and you'll see Joe the blacksmith,
and what larks we'll have!
But here, Pip, here I am most awful dull.
So God bless you, dear old Pip, old chap.
God bless you!
You know the way.
Pip.
How do you do?
You kiss my hand as if I was a queen.
- You wished to see me?
- Mm.
Pip.
I am to be sent to London.
I am to go on show, myself and the jewels.
Do you wish to go on show?
Why ask?
We have no choice, you and I,
but to obey instructions.
I watched you, you know, that day.
Fighting for my honour.
I must have been a strange little creature
to hide and watch, but I did.
I enjoyed it very much.
You rewarded me very much.
Did I?
You kissed me.
Poor Pip.
You imagine yourself a young knight
from a child's story,
tearing away the cobwebs and thorns,
letting in the sunshine.
Marrying the princess.
But you must know, Pip, I have no heart.
I don't believe it. How can there
be beauty without a heart?
Oh, I have a heart to be stabbed in or shot in,
and if it ceased to beat, I should cease to be.
But there's no softness there.
No sym path?
Sentiment.
Nonsense. I've been made that way.
- Oh, I...
- I am serious, Pip.
If we're to be thrown together,
you must believe me.
For both our sakes.
I'm sorry, I cannot.
I will not.
Very well. It is said at any rate.
Come, Miss Havisham will be
expecting you at your old post.
Is she beautiful?
Is she graceful?
Is she well-grown?
Do you admire her?
- Of course.
- Then love her. Love her, Pip.
If she wounds you, love her.
If she fails you, love her.
If she tears your heart to pieces,
as it gets older, it will tear deeper,
but love her, love her, love her!
I adopted her to be loved.
I bred her to be loved.
I educated her and I developed her
into what she is.
You know what love is, Pip?
It is blind devotion.
It is self-humiliation.
It is degradation.
It is utter submission, giving up
your heart and soul as I did to that man.
Miss Havisham!
Enough excitement for one day.
Pip, you've been requested to escort
Estella to London in the morning.
I suggest an early night.
Miss Havisham.
Shall we take a trip?
Once round?
♪ Old Clem, ♪
♪ with a thump and a sound ♪
♪ Old Clem ♪
♪ Beat it out, beat it out ♪
♪ Old Clem with a... ♪
Mrs Brandley is to be paid a large
sum of money to introduce me to society.
The jewels and I.
- We are to be shown to people...
- Hurry up!
...and people are to be shown to us.
- And may I come and see you?
- Of course.
Miss Havisham expects it.
If my time permits.
I see bills from vintners,
bills from jewellers, from bookmakers.
I suspected you would go wrong, Pip,
but really you are excelling yourself.
I'll endeavour to show more restraint.
Oh, do as you will, it's no business of mine.
Will you make sure that Mr Pip gets the money
he requires. Thank you, Wemmick?
Excuse me.
Ah. Good day to you, sir.
Please come into my office.
So good to see you again.
Finches, Finches, I would like to raise a glass
to a lady of my acquaintance.
Ooh!
A lady of Richmond.
A peerless beauty.
Miss Estella Havisham!
- Miss Estella Havisham!
- I know that lady.
Do you?
Oh, Lord
And you know nothing of her!
Well, on the contrary,
I've had the pleasure of dancing with her.
- Several times.
- You lie!
Steady now, Handel.
Indeed.
Then perhaps you might care to follow me.
Out of my way!
Step away from the lady, sir.
A waltz!
- The dance is not yet over.
- Remove your hand, sir.
Oh, hard luck. Come on.
Pip, will you never take warning?
- How can you do it, Estella?
- What?
Give your affections to that man.
All sorts of ugly creatures
hover about a lighted candle.
- Can the candle help it?
- No, but you can.
Perhaps. If I cared.
But you must care!
To encourage a man as despised,
as unworthy and boorish
as Bentley Drummle.
And this is a man who has nothing
to recommend him except money...
Pip, don't let it affect you so.
I can't help it!
To give that man the looks and smiles
you never give to me...
Do you want me to deceive you?
- Do you deceive him?
- Yes!
Yes, him and many, many other men.
All men.
All men but you.
And why am I to be spared?
Why do you think?
Lovely evening, isn't it?
A storm later, so they say.
Estella, Mr Drummle requires your presence.
Urgently.
Hello?
Herbert?
You're back early!
Who's there?
Who are you?
Wait, wait, wait. Shh. Wait.
How'd you get in here?
Good God.
What are you...
You acted noble, my boy.
Noble and I have never forgot it.
Look, if you're grateful to me
for what I did as a boy,
it's not necessary.
- Really. You must understand.
- What must I understand?
That I cannot renew our acquaintance.
My life has changed since then.
Now, I'm glad that you're well
and you've repented.
But really, you must go.
Please.
How about a drink first?
Before I go.
How have you been living?
A sheep farmer,
stock breeder, in the New World.
Many a thousand mile off.
- You've done well?
- I've done wonderful well.
Seems, you've done well, too.
Yes.
Yes. No, I have. Thank you.
I would like, if I may,
to give you this gift.
A token. For old times.
Before you go.
There's your gift.
Might a varmint make so bold
as to ask you, how you've done well...
Since we were anthem marshes?
Mmmm?
I've come into some property.
And might he ask whose property?
No, I cannot say her name.
There are conditions.
Conditions?
Could I make a guess as to your income?
Might the first figure be a...
A five?
- How could you...
- And you would have had a guardian?
A lawyer, maybe, with a name beginning with a...
AJ?
AJ, perhaps, who might have sent me
your address when I landed in Portsmouth?
Mr Jaggers, perhaps?
Yes, dear boy. Yes.
I've made a gentleman of you.
I swore that time
as sure as I ever earned a guinea,
that guinea should go to you.
No...
I lived rough that you should live smooth.
I worked hard that you should be above work.
I made you!
I'm your, your father, Pip.
No. No, no, no.
You are not my father!
No, no.
Your second father, then.
You're my son. No...
No, you're more to me than any son.
Look at you, dear boy!
Look at these lodgings.
They're fit for a lord.
And yeah, this watch and this ring
and your linen and your clothes.
And your, your books, too.
Oh!
You read them all, have you?
You shall read them to me...
And I shall be so proud, to think that
I'm the maker of such a man.
I must sleep, long and sound.
It's a long time since I slept.
You'll keep watch, dear boy?
Cos, look here. Here.
Caution is necessary.
I was sent for life.
It's death to come back.
I should be hanged if took.
You risked your life to come to me?
That's right, dear boy.
I... I don't even
know your name.
Magwitch.
Abel Magwitch.
Well, is it true?
Do not commit yourself.
Do not tell me anything,
I do not want...
- Is what I've been told true?
- "Told" implies verbal communication.
You cannot have verbal communication
with a man in New South Wales.
- I was always led to believe...
- Nothing.
Nothing.
You believed what you chose to believe.
Mmm-hmm?
It's not my responsibility.
Now, I understand you have
an uncle staying with you.
Yes? Yes?
- Yes.
- Right.
May I, suggest you buy him some new clothes,
advise him to spend most of his time
in your rooms
and perhaps have a haircut.
Yes?
Meanwhile, if you are writing to
your friend in New South Wales,
you may choose to send him that.
The balance of our accounts.
Mmm-hmm?
My services are ended.
Good day, Mr Pip.
All that time, in Satis House, I was just a...
A mechanical heart to practise on.
Estella was never meant for me at all.
And you, my "guardian",
have known this all along.
Well...
You may as well hear this from me
as anyone else.
Um...
The Spider has played his hand.
Can I help you?
- Open this gate, Drummle, or I swear...
- Why, it's the smithy's boy!
Don't lose your temper, smithy's boy.
Seems to me you've lost quite enough already.
Pip?
- Pip.
- Oh, enough!
What I have to say to Estella
I will say before you.
But, Miss Havisham...
When you first took me from my home,
I came as a kind of servant,
to gratify a whim and be paid for it.
Yes.
And when I fell into my mistake of
imagining that you were my benefactor...
Yes, I... Let you go on.
Was that kind?
Kind? Who am I to be kind?
No, it amused me...
To punish my relations.
You were adequately paid, I believe.
What else do you want?
Estella.
You know I love you.
I have loved you since
I first saw you in this house.
Foolishly, I had hoped that Miss Havisham
had meant us for each other.
Clearly the idea was absurd,
and I hope Miss Havisham will take
what pleasure she can
in knowing that I am as unhappy
as she ever meant me to be.
These are sentiments,
emotions that I am unable to comprehend.
When you say you love me,
I understand it as a form of words
but it touches nothing here.
- I don't believe you.
- Did I not warn you?
- Yes.
- Did you not think I meant it?
- No. It's not natural!
- It is natural in me!
And yet still I love you.
I know that I'll never call you mine, Estella,
yet still I love you.
I love you and I beg you
do not marry Bentley Drummle.
Someone else, anyone, but not that brute.
Too late. It's too late.
I am going to marry him.
The preparations are already under way.
- You can't let Miss Havisham...
- it is my own act.
Miss Havisham has urged me to wait,
to reconsider.
But I am tired of my life.
We will do well enough.
Give me your hand.
Be happy, Pip.
This will pass in time.
I'll be out of your thoughts in a week.
Out of my thoughts?
You're in every thought.
You're part of my existence.
You're part of me.
You're in every thought,
in every line I have ever read since
I first came here.
You're in the river,
the sails of ships,
the sea, the clouds,
the stones of London.
Until the last hours of my life,
you will remain in me...
Part of the little good, part of the evil.
And I will always think of the good.
Goodbye. God bless you.
So proud, so hard.
I am what you have made me!
You are my mother,
and yet I have never seen your face by daylight.
Since I was a baby, you taught me
that there was no such thing as daylight,
that it had blighted you...
And it would blight me, too, if I let it.
Well...
I am what you made me.
This is what you made me.
Estella...
Come with me now.
I'd like to help Mr Pocket.
He has been a loyal and decent friend
and I'd like to use the money
that remains to do one good thing.
I'd like to purchase him a position.
Without his knowledge.
Allowing for debts, which are substantial,
I might add, that's 500 pounds, sir.
- All invested in a friend?
- Yes, yes. Every last penny.
What's your advice?
Well, sir, if I was in the office, I would
suggest that you take that 500 pounds,
and choose your bridge.
There are 6 to choose from up
as high as Chelsea Reach
and throw the money off it.
You'll lose it just the same,
but it will be quicker and less painful.
Those would be my sentiments, in the office.
But your home sentiments, your...
Your Walworth sentiments?
My Walworth sentiments...
Would be...
I'm gonna see what I can do.
- Let go of me!
- Magwitch!
Leave him! Magwitch!
He wishes to buy us a house!
In Hyde Park!
- A coach, horses...
- Can't you accept?
How can I?
I've seen him try to murder a man.
He might have murdered you.
And yet, he risked his life to find you.
He says I am the son he's never had.
The idea appals me, Herbert,
but even so, he must not be captured...
Gentlemen.
Now, I ain't gonna tell you my life
like a song or a story book,
but give it to you short and handy.
In jail, out of jail.
That's my life...
Until I met my boy here.
I've been done everything to except hanged.
I've ramped and begged and thieved, poached...
Anything that doesn't pay and leads to trouble.
And then a matter of 20 years ago,
when I was out of money and out of luck,
not that I'd been in it much,
I met a man.
At Epsom races.
His name...
was Compeyson.
- Compeysun?
- Compeyson.
I'm sorry. Go on.
A gentleman was Compeyson,
a smooth one, good-looking too,
went to boarding school.
He was younger than me but he'd
got craft and he'd got learning.
He and his missus had a plan...
Involving the defrauding of
a certain lady by her half-brother.
It weren't much of a plan to my mind,
but I played my part...
I played my part in a small way.
I can't say I'm proud of it.
Well done, Abel.
I had a missus, too, at that time.
- You were married?
- No matter.
That was a dark time, that time with Compeyson.
Always in debt to him, always under his thumb,
always getting into danger,
always working, for years and years,
till I was his black slave.
The short of it is, we got committed for felony,
putting forged notes into circulation.
"Separate defences," Compeyson says.
"No communication."
I sold everything but the clothes
on my back so I could get Jaggers,
for all the good it did me.
Says the counsel for Compeyson,
wasn't he the younger
and well brought up and of a good school?
- Wasn't he...
- A gentleman of a county of Shropshire...
A gentleman?
Given your persistence
and your malign influence...
And when the verdict came, wasn't it Compeyson
as was recommended for mercy
on account of good character
and bad company and all the damn'd lies
he'd given up against me?
And wasn't it me as never got a word...
- But to find you guilty.
- Guilty.
- Order! Order!
Guilty.
For how long?
14 years.
He got two.
And a few months on,
he turns up on my prison ship.
I swore to the Lord, I'd smash his face in...
And I did.
And then, thinking, hoping, that he'd drowned,
I swam to the shore
and was hiding among the graves there,
envying them that were in them...
And my boy here found me.
My boy.
- Is he dead?
- Who?
Compeyson.
He'll wish I am, if he's alive.
And he'll wish he was, if I find him.
- And the lady he defrauded. Her name was...
- 'Avisham.
Miss 'Avisham.
I need you to tell me
about Compeyson.
Clever fellow Dangerous.
- Is he still alive?
- To my knowledge, yes.
I would strongly advise your uncle
to pack his bags.
If he's found, he will hang.
And it's fair to presume that
Mr Compeyson does not wish him well.
Abel's come back!
- You told me he'd never come back.
- Calm down, Molly.
He mustn't find out, ever.
Poor, poor, Abel.
What did you make me do?
It was wicked, wicked!
Abel will never find out.
I'll shall ensure that.
- Did I not swear at the time...
- You swore that she'd be safe!
You swore she'd have
a brand-new life!
Jaggers, you must tell me.
Who is this "she"?
Magwitch and Molly had a child.
A girl. A pretty thing.
But Molly was a fierce one,
wild and passionate like her husband,
and not a woman to let injustice
go unpunished.
Compeyson, of course, was safe in prison.
His wife, however, was not safe.
Molly found her.
A terrible crime.
Cold-blooded and ruthless,
assuming, of course, that Molly did it.
But to be guilty and to be found guilty
are different things.
Put the case that a woman accused
of murder went to see her
legal adviser...
And put the case that same legal
adviser holds a trust to find a child
for an eccentric and rich woman
to adopt and bring up.
Put the case that the legal adviser
said to the mother of the child...
Give the child into my hands,
I will do my best to get you off.
If you are saved, your child is saved.
If you are lost, your child is still saved.
And the child was your fee?
And what of Magwitch?
- The father was told...
- No! You say his name!
Magwitch was told that the child had died.
Consumption.
Put the case that she is now safe and wealthy,
and about to marry
one of the richest men in England.
And one of the vilest.
Estella is not the Spider's reward.
Estella is his punishment.
And you arranged it.
As instructed by my client.
Only as instructed.
And what did Miss Havisham
want with the child?
Well, you, uh,
must ask her yourself.
What did you want with the child?
I just wanted a little girl,
to love, and to rear,
to save from my fate.
One night he brought her here...
And I called her Estella.
Pip, she was so gentle.
She was so beautiful.
Pip, believe me,
when she first came to me,
I just meant to save her
from misery like my own.
But as she grew more beautiful,
I gradually did worse.
And with my praises
and my jewels and my teachings,
I... I stole her heart away...
And put ice in its place.
I stole her heart away...
Pip, are you very unhappy?
Do you hate me very much?
I know you must hate me,
but if you can ever bear to forgive me...
Forgive me.
Forgive me. Forgive me.
I won't deny there have been too many secrets.
But who would the truth serve?
If Estella...
Were to discover that her father is a convict,
her mother a murderess,
would she thank you, do you think?
Hmm?
Sir. A note for you.
Most important, the gentleman said.
Bastard! Where are you?
Show your bitchy face!
- Did you destroy my note?
- I did.
Best not to leave any evidence.
They're on to him, Mr Pip.
Police.
The reward on his head is substantial.
Every copper and cutthroat in London
is on the hunt for your Antipodean Uncle.
It was all your Mr Herbert and I could do
to get him out in time.
How do we get him away?
There's a steamer leaving
for Antwerp at midnight.
You and your Uncle find a way onto it.
Portable property, Mr Pip.
Try and lay hold of portable property.
All is well, Handel. He's quite safe here.
Though he is keen to see you.
- Goodness! What happened to your hands?
- Where is he?
Listen, the steamer departs at midnight.
We'll intercept it shortly after.
The further from the city we can get,
the safer it will be.
It's not long now.
Thank 'ee, my boy.
- I love you.
- Herbert...
Clara, I will return your
fiancee safely, I swear.
Apologies, Handel.
She thinks you have rather
a malign influence on me.
And she's right.
Herbert, are you sure you want to...
Handel, I don't think I've ever been
more excited in my life!
"The rain pattered dismally against the panes,
"and my candle was nearly burnt out,
"when, by the glimmer
of the half-extinguished light,
"I saw the dull yellow eye
of the creature open...
"It breathed."
Something wrong, Abel?
Not a bit of it.
To sit here and have my smoke
along with my dear boy...
I had a little child once.
I didn't tell you afore.
Pretty little thing. A girl.
Died while I was in prison.
But there weren't a day,
as I was rotting on that hulk,
when I didn't think on her face
and what a dear, pretty thing she were.
And when I saw you on them marshes,
well, you brought her to my mind.
Maybe that's why I took to you so strong.
I hope I've been a friend to you
this little time we've had.
You speak as if we're parting.
In an hour, we'll be safe aboard.
We can no more see to the bottom
of the next few hours
than we can see to the bottom of this river.
Which I catches in my hand.
And it's run through my fingers and gone.
You see?
Listen!
Can you hear?
Get the oars.
We'll head down the river and wait.
Go, boys. Go!
Come on, boys, row!
- Stop! Stop that boat!
- There they are!
Go on, boys!
Put your back into it!
Row!
You have a returned convict there!
His name is Abel Magwitch.
I apprehend the man,
and call upon him to surrender!
Keep going!
Compeyson.
Row!
Stop! Stop that boat!
Nearly there!
Turn!
Come on, boys!
They're closing on us!
No! No!
Get off!
Handel! Handel!
- Hang on!
- Magwitch, grab my hand!
- Look out, Pip!
- Aargh!
Pip!
- Magwitch!
- We have to get over there!
No!
Magwitch!
Up you come. Give me your hand.
Give me your hand.
Just get in there!
Come on.
- Abel!
- Handel, don't.
No.
Abel!
All is lost.
All is gone.
You've let the whole thing
slip through your fingers.
- Will he be tried?
- Yes.
He will be tried and found guilty, too,
and hanged.
The best that we can hope for
is that he dies before it comes to that.
The money, the land,
are all forfeit to the crown.
You have nothing, Pip.
Not a penny.
Can we keep that from him?
I'd like him to think I'm a gentleman still.
I must, amongst you, single out a miserable man
who, after many years of living
a peaceable and honest life in exile,
decided, in a fatal moment,
to return to the country
where he was expressly proscribed.
Whatever the motive for his return,
there can only be one punishment.
A punishment he shall share
with all of you here before me today.
By the power vested in me by this court,
I sentence you all to death by hanging.
May the Lord have mercy on your souls.
Are you in much pain today?
I don't complain, dear boy.
If only you had stayed away...
And not seen this face?
I... I wish I had been
more deserving of your love.
Hush.
A gentleman.
My very own.
Magwitch, I must tell you.
Your daughter...
Whom you loved and lost...
She lived.
She lived, and found powerful friends.
She is living now.
She is a lady and very beautiful.
And I... I love her.
I don't know you.
Concerns a debt, sir.
125 pounds 15 and 6.
- I don't have it.
- We didn't think so, sir.
So we've come to arrest you.
Would you come with us, please, sir?
Yes.
Yes, of course.
- Hello there.
- Is it Joe?
Which it is, old chap.
Forgive me, Joe.
Dear old Pip, old chap,
you and me was ever friends.
Now, you sleep...
And when you're well enough, what larks!
"Paid in full."
"Paid."
I came as quickly as I could.
I wanted to tell you...
on, Pip.
It's my wedding day!
Biddy, I can't for the life of me get...
Pip.
Oh, Pip!
- Oh!
- Biddy!
Oh!
Right, this way! Come on!
Forward, troops!
Come on! Or I'll carry
you like a big bird
and fly like a bird all the way over there.
Come on, Mrs Gargery.
One, two, three, four.
Oh! Oh, my poor old back!
What have you been eating?
Pip! Whoo!
- Your life savings, Joe!
- It's only money, Pip.
Nevertheless, I will work.
I will pay you back every penny,
if it takes me...
Pip. That's enough.
- Father! Father!
- Charles, be quiet.
How many times do I need to tell you, this
is a place of business, not a nursery!
I have a letter. Given by a lady.
Oh, a lady.
How intriguing!
Handel! You've a letter.
Drummle died 2 years ago.
He was kicking his horse,
and the horse kicked back.
I'm sorry to hear that.
Pip...
I'm sorry for anything that brings you sorrow.
Well, rest assured I feel none.
My husband and I made each other
perfectly miserable, just as intended.
I have been bent and broken...
But I hope into a better shape.
I've been travelling a great deal.
I had heard that you were here, and thriving...
And I had a desire to see my old friend.
My only friend.
When we last met,
you said that you would always think of me.
And I have.
- That you would think of the good in me.
- Always.
You are a part of me, Estella.
"You are in the ships", you said,
"And the river."
I love you, Estella.
I'm glad.